<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OS on Behouba Manassé Kouamé</title><link>https://behouba.github.io/behouba.github.io/tags/os/</link><description>Recent content in OS on Behouba Manassé Kouamé</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Behouba Manassé Kouamé</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 18:45:52 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://behouba.github.io/behouba.github.io/tags/os/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Discovering Kernel Fuzzing</title><link>https://behouba.github.io/behouba.github.io/2022/08/discovering-kernel-fuzzing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 18:45:52 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://behouba.github.io/behouba.github.io/2022/08/discovering-kernel-fuzzing/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year, during an industrial project that is part of my master&amp;rsquo;s program, I had the opportunity to make my first steps into the world of kernel fuzzing. This was a great learning experience, during which I had the opportunity to work with wonderful people. In this blog post, I will describe my journey into the world of kernel fuzzing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have to admit that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about fuzzing when I was finishing my first semester of the Master of Software Engineering at &lt;a href="https://innopolis.university/en/">Innopolis University&lt;/a>. Before the end of the first semester, we have to choose an industrial project for the next semester. To do so, we attended multiple project presentation sessions with representatives of different companies. During the project presentations, we were presented with many interesting projects covering various areas of software engineering. One project from KasperskyLab was the most appealing to me; I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly why, since I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about the project before the presentation. But I think it was because I wanted to learn something outside of my comfort zone. The project was presented by Anna Melekhova, a senior engineer at KasperskyLab. The project was about researching kernel fuzzing approaches and their implementation for Kaspersky OS, a new operating system in development at KasperskyLab. I chose this project and got it accepted along with four other classmates.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>