<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Behouba Manassé K</title>
    <link>https://behouba.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Behouba Manassé K</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Behouba Manassé Kouamé</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 11:25:52 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://behouba.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memory Forensics analysis of container checkpoints with checkpointctl</title>
      <link>https://behouba.github.io/2023/10/memory-forensics-analysis-of-container-checkpoints-with-checkpointctl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 11:25:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://behouba.github.io/2023/10/memory-forensics-analysis-of-container-checkpoints-with-checkpointctl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the field of computer science, forensic analysis, also known as computer forensics, is a specialized domain that focuses on the extraction of evidence from electronic devices and digital data. Forensic analysis goals are to identify, preserve, recover, analyze, and ultimately present factual information and expert opinions about cybercrimes or other digital activities. The computer forensic analyst uses various techniques and tools to guide his investigations. Tools such as Wireshark, Volatility, Autopsy, and others are popular forensic analysis tools across various operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Kernel Fuzzing</title>
      <link>https://behouba.github.io/2022/08/discovering-kernel-fuzzing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 18:45:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://behouba.github.io/2022/08/discovering-kernel-fuzzing/</guid>
      <description>This year, during an industrial project that is part of my master&amp;rsquo;s program, I had the opportunity to make my first steps into the world of kernel fuzzing. This was a great learning experience, during which I had the opportunity to work with wonderful people. In this blog post, I will describe my journey into the world of kernel fuzzing.&#xA;I have to admit that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about fuzzing when I was finishing my first semester of the Master of Software Engineering at Innopolis University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happens When You Boot Your LInux System</title>
      <link>https://behouba.github.io/2020/03/what-happens-when-you-boot-your-linux-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 18:45:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://behouba.github.io/2020/03/what-happens-when-you-boot-your-linux-system/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what’s really going on when you press the power button on your Linux machine? I mean, sure, you see your distribution logo, maybe a loading spinner, and then the login screen. But what’s happening under the hood? Let’s take a journey together, from the moment you hit that power button to when you’re greeted by the login screen. I’ll explain this process for Fedora which is my favorite Linux distribution!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
